Guide to the Bright Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Bright Family Papers
1911-1989
RG 130
Yale University Divinity School Library
8
(19 boxes)
J. Homer and Minnie Bright, their son J. Calvin Bright, and his wife Harriet Bright, were American missionaries in China from 1911 to 1951, serving under the Church of the Brethren mission. The elder Brights served in Shao Yang and Ping Ting, Shansi province. J. Calvin and Harriet Bright served in Chengtu, Szechwan province. This record group also contains material related to Daniel and Jane Dye, who taught at the West China Union University in Chengtu. J. Calvin and Harriet Bright were Church of the Brethren ministers in Indiana and Illinois after 1951.
Bright, J. Calvin
Bright, Harriet
Bright, J. Homer
Bright, Minnie Flory
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Bright family
Biographical / Historical
J. Homer and Minnie Bright, their son J. Calvin Bright, and his wife Harriet Bright were American missionaries in China from 1911 to 1951,serving under the Church of the Brethren mission. J. Calvin and Harriet Bright were Church of the Brethren ministers in Indiana and Illinois after 1951.
Scope and Contents
I. Papers of J. Homer Bright
II. Papers of Minnie Bright
III. Papers of J. Calvin Bright
IV. Papers of Harriet Bright
V. Collected Material
VI. Photographs
These papers provide valuable information about the work of the Church of the Brethren in China. They complement the papers of other Church of the Brethren missionaries that are held at the Yale Divinity Library, including the Ikenberry Papers (Record Group No. 168) and the Daryl and Martha Neiderhiser Parker papers in Record Group No. 8. J. Calvin and Harriet Bright were close colleagues with Daniel and Jane Balderston Dye while serving in West China and the Bright Papers contain correspondence with Daniel Dye and other materials that complement the Dye Papers of Record Group No. 22. Two boxes of Dye correspondence received with the Bright Papers have been transferred to the Dye Papers.
Arrangement
I. Papers of J. Homer Bright
II. Papers of Minnie Bright
III. Papers of J. Calvin Bright
IV. Papers of Harriet Bright
V. Collected Material
VI. Photographs
Missions -- China; Women missionaries; Missionaries; Church of the Brethren. General Mission Board
- Papers of J. Homer Bright, Series I
  - Family Correspondence
    - Letters to/from family, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Letters to/from family, 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
    - Letters to/from family, 1928-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7-19)
    - Letters to/from family, 1949-1961, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20-23)
  - General Correspondence
    - American Consular Service, 1925-1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Beggs, Gertrude, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Beggs, Gertrude, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Fitz to G. Beggs, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bonsack, Chas, 1935-1941 (Box 2, Folder 28-31)
    - Bridger, F.C., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bowmaw, Rufus, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Brubaker, Leland, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Caxton Press, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Culp, Clyde, 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 36-38)
    - Culp, Clyde to M. Myers, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Dye, D.S., 1949, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
    - Flory, Wendell to L. Brubaker, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Griggs, K., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Grimes, A.C., 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
    - Grimes, A.C. to F.C. Bridger, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Heoff, E.B., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Hillmer, Helen, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Koo, T.K., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Lund, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - McCoy, L.M., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Mackenzie, Hugh, 1929-1939 (Box 2, Folder 52-55)
    - McCann, James, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Mow, Anetta, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Myers, Minor, 1935-1941 (Box 2, Folder 58-63)
    - Oriental Luggage Factory, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Pettus, W.B., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Smith, Russell J., 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Smith, W.H., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Snapper, Dean, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Sollenberger, O.C. to Leland Brubaker, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Thomson, Lillian, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Tucker, E.B., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Wampler, R.C., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Westernport Church of the Brethren, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Winger, Otho, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Yin, Peter C.T., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - misc., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Papers of Minnie Bright (wife of J. Homer Bright), Series II
  - Family correspondence
    - Letter to/from family, 1911-1919 (Box 3, Folder 77-85)
    - Letters to/from family, 1920-1931 (Box 4, Folder 86-98)
    - Letters to/from family, 1932-1938 (Box 5, Folder 99-106)
    - Letters to/from family, 1939-1951, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 107-110)
  - General Correspondence
    - Brother Danner, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Coomb, J.C., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Daryl, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Hsing, Y.T., 1940 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Mackenzie, Hugh, 1938, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 115-116)
    - Mow, Anetta, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Mow, Anetta, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Yen, Chang Kiang, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Writing/Papers
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - Letters re: Minnie Bright's illness, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Minerva Metzger Memorium, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 122)
      - Writings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 123-124)
- Papers of J. Calvin Bright, Series III
  - Family Correspondence: JCB to family
    - JCB to family, 1925-1973 (Box 6, Folder 125-139)
    - JCB to family, 1975, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 140-141)
  - Family Correspondence: Family to JCB
    - Family to JCB, 1933-1965, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142-147)
  - Correspondence with Daniel S. Dye
    - DSD to JCB, 1950-1964 (Box 7, Folder 148-162)
    - DSD to JCB, 1965-1977, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 163-172)
    - JCB to DSD, 1949-1977, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 173-187)
  - Correspondence with Portia Mickey
    - JCB to PM, 1958-1961, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 188-191)
    - PM to JCB, 1956-1961, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 192-197)
  - Other general correspondence
    - Beaver, Rufus, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Beggs, Gertrude, 1936-1937 (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - Blacklock, Jeannie, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Bowman, Rufus, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Bright Easter letter, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - Brubaker, Leland, 1947-1951 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Cowan, Celia / Knettler, Ed and Jean (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Crim, Bessie / Harvey, Earl, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - Edwards, Robert / Moncrieff, Jesse, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - Edwards, Theodore, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Erickson, Alma / Van Meter, Herbert, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - Graham, David, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Huggins, Margaret, 1961, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 210-211)
    - Kilborn, Leslie and Jean, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - King, Rufus / Bowman, Loren, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - Klepinger / Kiracofe / Wogaman, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - Lambert, Lyle, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 215)
    - Lee, Carl Q., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - Li, J.T., 1934 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - Martin, Rose S., 1936 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - McCoy, Lewistine, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - Manlore, Donald, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - Moncrieff, Jessie, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - Morris, Raymond P, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Outerbridge, Ralph, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Overbridges, R, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - Parsons, Maud, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - Proctor, Orvia, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Quale, G. Robina, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Robertson, Marjorie, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Robinson, A. G., 1935 (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - Rosen, Steven, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Russell, Harl, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Ryding, Stanley W., 1952 (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Salem Church, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - Shull, Merlin, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Stockwell, Olin, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - Studabaker, Ben, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Taylor, Walter to Charles Zunkel, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Tucker, Emma, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - Walmsley, Lewis C., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - Winens, Edward, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - Yang, Jeanne, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 242-243)
  - Writings/papers
    - Calvin's New Testament, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - Message from prison, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 244a)
    - Biography, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244b)
    - Financial papers, 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 244c)
    - Medical history, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - Article about Gladys Aylworth, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244e)
- Papers of Harriet Bright, Series IV
  - Correspondence
    - Various, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 245-248)
    - Parsons, Maud, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - Writings/papers
    - Obituary, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 251)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 252)
- Collected material, Series V
  - China mission materials (primarily Church of the Brethren)
    - Map showing distribution of missionaries, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Report of Friends West China Mission, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 291)
    - English Service at Bright home, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 292)
    - American Consular Service, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 293)
    - Death of Sister Cripe, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 294)
    - Report of Shouyang Station, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 295)
    - H. Bright to Field Committee, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 296)
    - Committee on East Asia, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 297)
    - Wampler, Ernest, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 298)
    - General Mission Board - Church of the Brethren, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 299)
    - Report on Special Mission to China, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 300)
    - Field Committee Meeting, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 301)
    - Parker family, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 302)
    - Letters from missionaries, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 303)
    - C. Bright to Annual Conference, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 304)
    - H. Rothrock to China friends, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 305)
    - D. Phelps to University Community Church, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 306)
    - Peking Conference, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 307)
    - C. Bright to Commission on Ministry and Missions, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 308)
    - Biography of Dr. Frances Tucker, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 309)
    - Church of the Brethren Organization, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 310)
    - Report of the General Brotherhood Board, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 311)
    - Letter about state of China at start of Communist rule, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 312)
    - Building plans, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 313)
    - Brethren General Health Cooperative Plan, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 314)
    - Brethren Rural Service Center, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 315)
    - Pamphlet - General Mission Board / Church of the Brethren, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 316)
    - Courageous Statemanship in Missions, Alexander McLeish (Box 12, Folder 317)
    - Experiences in Quest of a New Field, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Weaving in Chengtu, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 319)
    - Trinity Theological College, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 320)
    - The Japan International Christian University Foundation (Box 12, Folder 321)
  - Mission finance
    - Statements, 1931-1934 (Box 12, Folder 322)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1936 (Box 12, Folder 323)
    - Financial Report, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 324)
    - Advance Statement, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 325)
    - Yearly Treasurer's Report, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 326)
    - Misc., 1933-1935 (Box 12, Folder 327)
    - Authorized Payroll, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 328)
    - Financial Papers, Shouyang Relief, 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 329)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1940, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 330-332)
  - North China American School
    - Alumni Bulletin, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 333)
    - Commencement Exercises, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 334)
    - Statements, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 335)
  - Church of the Brethren (general)
    - Annual Conference, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 336)
    - God's Quiet Heroes, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 337)
    - For the Pastor's Corner, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 338)
    - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 339)
    - Wabash, Indiana (Box 12, Folder 340)
    - Cripe, C.C., 1952 (Box 12, Folder 341)
  - Weaving materials of Harriet Bright
    - Weaving samples and miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Weaving samples and miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Weaving samples and miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Miscellany
    - Cards, postcards, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - Telegrams, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Misc. letters, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - Hotel Du Tcheng Tai, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - Tali Funeral Rites by Yung-Ch'un Ts'ai, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - China newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 347)
    - China Connection, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - The Far Eastern Travellers Gazette, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - The China Monthly, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 350)
    - The Battle for the Bible - The Word of God in and out of the Eclipse, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 351)
    - Autobiographical essay, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 352)
    - Chinese letters, characters, etc., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Lectures notes, misc., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 354)
    - Cloth picture of cats, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 355)
    - Psalms, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 356)
    - The Cross or Vicarious Suffering in the Christian Message, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 357)
    - Greater than the greatest of the Prophets, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 358)
    - Newspaper articles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 359)
    - Books of pictures, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 360)
    - Dried plants / Chinese Ink Drawings, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 361)
    - Book of pictures, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 362)
    - Incised Designs, Phillips, W.J., 1950 (Box 16, Folder 363)
    - Chinese Designs, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 364)
    - Articles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 365)
    - Map, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 366)
    - Invitation to Homer and Minnie Bright's 50th wedding anniversary (Box 17, Folder 367)
    - Chengtu News Bulletin, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 368)
    - Archaeology, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 369)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 370-371)
- Photographs, n.d.; Series VI
  - Wellwood, Robert, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 372)
  - Mrs. Jane Dye, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 373)
  - Negatives from China, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 374)
  - D.S. Dye, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 375)
  - Negatives, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 376)
  - Bright family, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 377)
  - Museum Exhibit Pictures, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 378)
  - Friends Yearly Meeting, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 379)
  - D.S. Dye, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 381-383)
  - Negatives, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - China / Mission photos (Box 18)
  - China/ Landscape and Architecture photos (Box 19)
  - China/ Mission photos (Box 11)